# CHRISTOPHER GEHRMANN

DATA SPECIALIST

San Diego, CA

christopher.gehrmann@gmail.com 916-599-2430 ♠ https://tophurkey.github.io/Data Projects/

in cjgehrmann

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a data-driven engineer in San Diego constantly growing his knowledge in Statistics and Data Pipelines building my toolbox of data analysis methods and practicing my presentation skills. I spend much of my free time teaching children, new grads, and adults programming and statistics while sharpening my own skills in Cluster Computing, Cloud Server Management, and Machine Learning. I currently work as a data specialist where I manage all servers, databases, and pipelines for critical infrastructure at ASML.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES	DASHBOARD	ANALYTICS	STATISTICS
Python	Flask, Django	Data Modelling	Hypothesis (A/B) Testing
R, Julia	HTML/CSS	SQL, MSSQL, MySQL	PCA, DOE
Java	Tableau Server	Pandas/SciKit Learn	Frequentist/Bayesian Analyses
Powershell, Bash	Javascript	Tableau, Regex	Regression, SVM, K-Means

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Data Specialist | ASML | San Diego, CA | Oct 2021 - Present

- Propose and configure data management solutions for analyzing utilities and infrastructure performance
- Technical Asset Manager for VM Clusters, Site Data Governance Lead, and Data Analytics Lead

#### **DATA PROJECTS:**

## **Critical System Recovery**

- Performed complete analysis of historical data for business-critical systems for RCA of 50% utilities downtime
- Using multiple data analysis techniques identified control system deficits and isolated issue leading to 95% uptime
- Providing data analysis to drive permanent automated solution for 99.85% uptime of all critical systems

## **Automate Dashboards for Internal Metrics Reporting**

- Created ETL pipeline to automate data acquisition from Service Ticket System including Text-to-Metric Analysis
- Automated Dashboards and PowerPoints with Data and present to Upper Management Weekly

## Senior Process Development Engineer | Dexcom | San Diego, CA | Dec 2020 - Present

- Discover ways to acquire and aggregate data from constantly changing sources during development.
- Create dashboards based on Executive Management feedback and Team needs for Performance Reports.

# **DATA PROJECT:**

## **Dashboard for Automation Line Performance**

- Prototyped Python Plotly Dashboard with Docker for visualizing line status and performance metrics
- Migrated data visualizations to Tableau and created custom graph components to meet management needs.
- Guiding architecture of SQL databases for use in future live data Dashboarding on launch.

## Process Development Engineer | Illumina | San Diego, CA | Nov 2018 - Dec 2020

- Coded a C# and SQL based SW for monitoring live production data on custom equipment for MFG Floor.
- Created installable SW with GUI to help non-coding engineers analyze large and complex FMEA documents.

# **DATA PROJECT:**

#### **Multi-Source Data Aggregation**

- Rewrote code from R to Python and added integration for accessing JIRA, MSSQL, Network Folders, and Custom SW.
- Trained the entire process engineering team to use python to run scripts for personal use.

#### Design Quality Engineer | Medtronic | San Jose, CA | January 2017 - Nov 2018

- -Utilized PANDAS and DASK to aggregate and filter entire MAUDE FDA Database for analysis.
- Automated the data acquisition and analysis to monitor risk over project lifetime.

## **DATA PROJECT:**

#### **MAUDE Database Analysis**

- Utilized PANDAS and DASK to aggregate and filter entire MAUDE FDA Database for analysis.
- Automated the data acquisition and analysis to monitor risk over project lifetime.

## Instructor and Chair | ASQ | San Diego, CA | Aug 2019 - Present

- Teach refresher courses and give presentations on Statistics for local Engineers.

## Research Assistant | University of Memphis | Memphis, TN | Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

- Created an automated program for assessing and creating data visualizations on novel protein assays.

## Co-Founder/Manager | UC Merced SATAL | Merced, CA | Sep 2009 - Aug 2012

- Created program for collecting and assessing feedback to improve pedagogical methods.

## **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Merced | 2012

B.S. Bioengineering

# University of Memphis & University of Tennessee Health Science Center | 2016

M.S. Biomedical Engineering